SUMMARY

In the role of a Data Analyst, specialization lies in utilizing data to drive strategic decision-making and operational excellence. Possessing a curious mind and a strong drive for learning, expertise is demonstrated in identifying connections between data sets and transforming challenges into opportunities through meticulous attention to detail. The background in music production, education, tourism management, and entrepreneurship collectively shapes an analytical mindset and communication skills, providing a distinctive perspective for data analysis in today's datadriven world.

CONTACT

O Portland, OR (Open to Remote / Relocation)

(908) 636-5891

http://euikyu.wixsite.com/euikyu

Linkedin: <u>/euikyu-kim</u>

Tableau Public: /euikyu.kim
 ☐

GitHub: /kimicue 🖸

EDUCATION

Certificate in Data Analytics

CareerFoundry, Remote, Berlin, Germany, 2023

Certificate in Data Design & SQL

Portland Comm. College, Portland, OR, 2020

Associate in Music Business (AA)

Bergen Comm. College, Paramus, NJ, 2015

Certificate in Film Scoring

UCLA Extension, Los Angeles, CA, 2010

Master of Digital Interactive Music (MM)

Dongguk University, Seoul, S. Korea, 2007

Bachelor in Tourism Management & English Translation/Interpretation

Kyunghee University, Seoul, S. Korea, 2003

SKILLS

SQL | Excel | Tableau | Python | PowerPoint | Keynote | Data Analytics & Visualization

LANGUAGE

English | Korean

Euikyu Kim Data Analyst

PROJECTS

Preparing for Influenza Season, Medical Staffing Guide

Applies data sourcing, profiling, pivoting, statistical analyzing hypothesis testing & visualizing to analyze the data & answer any ad-hoc business-related questions.

Tools: Excel & Tableau (Dashboard, Storyboard)

Interim Report: .pdf \(\overline{\mathbb{Z}} \) | Final Report: Tabeau \(\overline{\mathbb{Z}} \) | Presentation: YouTube \(\overline{\mathbb{Z}} \)

Rockbuster, Video Rental Sales

Applies data cleaning, joining, advanced filtering, common table expressions & subqueries to analyze the data & answer any ad-hoc business-related questions.

Instacart, Online Grocery Sales

Applies data wrangling, data quality & consistency checking, merging data frames, exploratory statistical analysis & data visualization using *Matplotlib* & *Seaborn*.

Tools: Python (pandas, numpy, scipy, matplotlib, seaborn) & Excel (Report)
Python Coding: .ipynb ☑ | Instacart Grocery Basket Analysis: .xlsx ᅶ

WORK EXPERIENCE

School Bus Driver (First Student, Portland, OR, 2021-2023)

Maintained records/documentation, problem solving, time management, unwavering reliability, attention to detail, customer service, safety consciousness, adaptability, teamwork, and communication, resulting in a safe and punctual student commute.

Computer Lab Assistant (Portland Community College, Portland, OR, 2018-2020)

Provided technical support, time/data management, customer service, problem solving, attention to detail, collaboration, analytical thinking, adaptability, and assistance to using computer resources, ensured proper functioning of equipment, and aided in troubleshooting software and hardware issues.

Tech Support Internship (Free Geek, Portland, OR, 2018-2019)

Assisted with learning agility, troubleshooting, and resolving hardware or software issues, while providing technical support. Demonstrated skills in time and data management, customer service, problem-solving, attention to detail, collaboration, and analytical thinking. Contributed to maintaining and optimizing computer systems.

Business Owner & Operator (tobaccoflower.co.kr, Portland, OR, 2010-2018)

Enhanced customer shopping experience through meticulous attention to detail in product descriptions, images, website design, data management, e-commerce, and communication, resulting in improved accuracy and responsiveness in customer service.

Instructor / Adjunct Professor, in Digital Sound & Music (2007-2009 & 2012)

- Korea Broadcasting Arts School, Seoul, South Korea, 2012
- Korea College of Media Arts, Sejong City, South Korea, 2007-2009
- Seoul Theological College, Seoul, South Korea, 2007-2008

Contributed in curriculum development, leadership, teamwork, problem solving, attention to detail, adaptability, presentation and effective feedback and assessment resulting in great teamwork, adaptability, and time and stress control.